[Home](https://www.scouting.org/) > [Legal](https://www.scouting.org/legal/) > Donor Privacy Policy

Donor Privacy Policy
====================

**The Boy Scouts of America (“BSA”)** is committed to respecting and protecting the personal privacy of its members and those who visit its website at www.scouting.org. The following is our donor privacy policy, which guides our staff on how they may use a donor’s personal information while honoring your rights as a contributor. We will not sell, share or trade our donor’s names or personal information with any other entity, nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations. This policy applies to all information received by **BSA**, both online and offline, on any Platform (“Platform,” includes the **BSA**‘s websites and mobile applications), as well as any electronic, written, or oral communications.

**BSA** uses personal identifiable information from donors that is collected at several points on our website, including: name, address, telephone number, email address and donor comments when a donor voluntarily provides it to us. When a donor pledges money as a donation, **BSA** requests certain personally identifiable information from them on our secure donation form and/or by telephone. Donors must provide contact information (such as name, email and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fulfill donations. Credit card information is only used for specific or pre-authorized recurring transaction(s) and is then destroyed. However, if we have trouble processing a donation, we will use this information to contact the donor.

In addition, a record is kept of each donor’s giving history. Donor information is stored on a **BSA** donor management database. Access to the database is restricted to personnel with legitimate business need to access or modify the information contained therein. This information is kept on file for IRS purposes and is also used for gift acknowledgment and mailing lists.

BSA does not sell, trade, rent or share names, addresses, telephone numbers or e-mail addresses of our donors. **BSA** will use contact information (e-mail, telephone numbers or addresses) of donors for these purposes only:

* Produce receipts for donations;
* Acknowledge donors for their contributions;
* Inform donors about news, upcoming fundraising events and Scouting activities; o When information is sent utilizing a mailing service – The companies we employ have access only to the personal information needed to perform their functions, but are contractually prohibited from using it for other purposes;
* Internal analysis and record keeping;
* If necessary, reporting to relevant U.S. agencies; and
* As a means of recognizing support, BSA may occasionally publish names of donors in various Scouting newsletters, brochures and publications. If a donor prefers their name not be published, please notify the Development Office at 972-580-2219.

**Online Donations**

Our donation button uses industry standard SSL (secure socket layer) technology to protect data transmissions. The information collected will not be given out (shared or sold) to any third party.

When giving an online donation, or making an activity registration payment, **BSA** takes every precaution to protect donor personal information. That includes online data collected on the **BSA** website through our secure e-commerce system and payment processor used to securely process online donations. All communications with the online processor are encrypted for the highest level of security of donor personal information.

If you have questions about this Donor Privacy Policy or if you wish to be removed from our e-mail and/or postal contact lists at any time, please contact the Development Office at 972-580-2219.

**NOTE:** This privacy policy was last modified on June 15, 2017 and applies only to the Boy Scouts of America and its websites, including www.scouting.org. This privacy policy does not apply to any BSA council or unit website, as their content is not controlled by the BSA. Please contact the administrator of any council, unit or other Scouting-oriented website for information about their own privacy policies and the information they collect about their site visitors.

#### BSA Resources

#### BSA Info

#### LEGAL

#### Connect With Us

[

](https://twitter.com/boyscouts)

[

](https://www.instagram.com/boyscoutsofamerica/)

[

](https://www.pinterest.com/boyscouts/)

[

](https://www.youtube.com/c/BoyScoutsofAmericavideos)

© 2024 Boy Scouts of America - All Rights Reserved  
Registered 501(c)(3). EIN: 22-1576300

Bray Barnes
-----------

Director, Global Security Innovative  
Strategies

Bray Barnes is a recipient of the Distinguished Eagle Scout Award, Silver  
Beaver, Silver Antelope, Silver Buffalo, and Learning for Life Distinguished  
Service Award. He received the Messengers of Peace Hero award from  
the royal family of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, and he’s a life member of  
the 101st Airborne Association and Vietnam Veterans Association. Barnes  
serves as a senior fellow for the Global Federation of Competitiveness  
Councils, a nonpartisan network of corporate CEOs, university presidents, and  
national laboratory directors. He has also served as a senior executive for the  
U.S. Department of Homeland Security, leading the first-responder program  
and has two U.S. presidential appointments

David Alexander
---------------

Managing Member Calje

David Alexander is a Baden-Powell Fellow, Summit Bechtel Reserve philanthropist, and recipient of the Silver Buffalo and Distinguished Eagle Scout Award. He is the founder of Caljet, one of the largest independent motor fuels terminals in the U.S. He has served the Arizona Petroleum Marketers Association, Teen Lifeline, and American Heart Association. A triathlete who has completed hundreds of races, Alexander has also mentored the women’s triathlon team at Arizona State University.

Glenn Adams
-----------

President, CEO & Managing Director  
Stonetex Oil Corp.

Glenn Adams is a recipient of the Silver Beaver, Silver Antelope, Silver Buffalo, and Distinguished Eagle Scout Award. He is the former president of the National Eagle Scout Association and established the Glenn A. and Melinda W. Adams National Eagle Scout Service Project of the Year Award. He has more than 40 years of experience in the oil, gas, and energy fields, including serving as a president, owner, and CEO. Adams has also received multiple service awards from the Texas Alliance of Energy Producers.
